Our world is complex and it's changing fast.
And in today's workplace, we are called to see opportunities for innovation
and also watch out for threats,
draw on different capabilities and expertise to solve complex challenges,
and make rapid decisions with many trade-offs.
Well, all this isn't an easy job for one person to tackle,
which is why teams have the potential to be so powerful.
Teams can make real breakthroughs because they have the potential
to adapt to the world around them better and faster than any individual on their own.
But not all teams do this well.
Think of the teams you worked with that were high-performing and enjoyable.
Now think of the teams that weren't.
At some point in our life, we've all been on a team
where we may have felt there was shaming and blaming team members for their mistakes.
We might have even sensed an unsettling tension around voicing different opinions
and a lack of desire to help each other learn and grow.
We probably describe it as an environment
where we didn't feel comfortable showing up as our full selves.
We might have felt the need to censor our ways in order to avoid backlash.
Or maybe we just weren't that invested
and so didn't participate as much as usual.
On the other hand, the most effective teams work and learn collaboratively,
building on each other's strengths and offsetting each other's weaknesses.
And to do that well, teams need psychological safety.
When we feel psychologically safe, we are willing to be creative and take risks,
bring our authentic selves to work,
know that expressing ideas and concerns is welcomed,
aren't afraid to admit mistakes and learn from them,
and believe we're valuable team members, even when we ask for help.
It's well researched that psychological safety is an important driver of performance.
Yet research has also found that probably less than a third of teams
actually experience psychological safety.
Imagine the benefits if we doubled or tripled that number.
Research suggests that doubling psychological safety would not only increase productivity,
it would reduce safety incidents and turnover,
helping to save money and improve employee well-being.
Other studies have found that hospital units with more error reporting had fewer deaths.
Why? Because when people hide errors, more mistakes happen.
The same is true in environments like manufacturing and mining,
where recognizing mistakes has a direct impact on physical safety.
More broadly, in psychologically safe environments,
employees perform better and they're more satisfied with their jobs.
Would you like to work on a team where you felt you could be your most comfortable,
competent, creative, risk-taking, mistake-making self?
It's within your power to help make this happen,
no matter the role you play on a team.
You have an opportunity to create a psychologically safe environment.
And in doing so, you can help your team be greater than the sum of its parts.